<measure>
  <schema_version>3.0</schema_version>
  <name>biased_economizer_sensor_outdoor_rh</name>
  <uid>cb5d34a2-7980-44bb-8a41-1f2cb262fd81</uid>
  <version_id>718b579b-e8e8-4525-9dc7-3f6e8a9e4f56</version_id>
  <version_modified>20171212T144505Z</version_modified>
  <xml_checksum>B7427881</xml_checksum>
  <class_name>BiasedEconomizerSensorOutdoorRH</class_name>
  <display_name>Biased Economizer Sensor: Outdoor RH</display_name>
  <description>When sensors drift and are not regularly calibrated, it causes a bias. Sensor readings often drift from their calibration with age, causing equipment control algorithms to produce outputs that deviate from their intended function. A positive bias in the economizer outdoor relative humidity (RH) sensor leads to a higher estimate in the outdoor air enthalpy, which shifts the economizer switch-off point and could cause higher cooling or heating energy consumption. This measure simulates the biased economizer sensor (outdoor air RH) by modifying the Controller:OutdoorAir object in EnergyPlus assigned to the heating and cooling system. The fault intensity (F) for this fault is defined as the biased RH level (%)</description>
  <modeler_description>Two user inputs are required, based on these user inputs, the outdoor air RH reading in the economizer will be replaced by the equation below, where RHoaF is the biased outdoor air RH reading, RHoa is the actual outdoor air RH, and F is the fault intensity. RHoaF = RHoa + F. To use this measure, choose the Controller:OutdoorAir object to be faulted. Set the level of relative humidity sensor bias between 0 to 1 that you want at the outdoor air duct for the economizer during the simulation period. For example, setting F=3 means the sensor is reading 25% when the actual relative humidity is 22%. You can also impose a schedule of the presence of fault during the simulation period. If a schedule name is not given, the model assumes that the fault is present during the entire simulation period.</modeler_description>
  <arguments>
    <argument>
      <name>econ_choice</name>
      <display_name>Enter the name of the faulted Controller:OutdoorAir object. To impose the fault on all economizers, enter * ALL Controller:OutdoorAir *</display_name>
      <type>String</type>
      <required>true</required>
      <model_dependent>false</model_dependent>
      <default_value>* ALL Controller:OutdoorAir *</default_value>
    </argument>
    <argument>
      <name>oa_rh_bias</name>
      <display_name>Enter the bias level of the return air relative humidity sensor. A positive number means that the sensor is reading a relative humidity higher than the true relative humidity. [%]</display_name>
      <type>Double</type>
      <required>false</required>
      <model_dependent>false</model_dependent>
      <default_value>0</default_value>
    </argument>
  </arguments>
  <outputs/>
  <provenances/>
  <tags>
    <tag>HVAC.HVAC Controls</tag>
  </tags>
  <attributes>
    <attribute>
      <name>Measure Type</name>
      <value>EnergyPlusMeasure</value>
      <datatype>string</datatype>
    </attribute>
    <attribute>
      <name>Intended Software Tool</name>
      <value>OpenStudio Application</value>
      <datatype>string</datatype>
    </attribute>
    <attribute>
      <name>Intended Software Tool</name>
      <value>Parametric Analysis Tool</value>
      <datatype>string</datatype>
    </attribute>
    <attribute>
      <name>Intended Software Tool</name>
      <value>Analysis Spreadsheet</value>
      <datatype>string</datatype>
    </attribute>
  </attributes>
  <files>
    <file>
      <version>
        <software_program>OpenStudio</software_program>
        <identifier>1.5.0</identifier>
        <min_compatible>1.5.0</min_compatible>
      </version>
      <filename>measure.rb</filename>
      <filetype>rb</filetype>
      <usage_type>script</usage_type>
      <checksum>0B63DE35</checksum>
    </file>
    <file>
      <filename>misc_eplus_func.rb</filename>
      <filetype>rb</filetype>
      <usage_type>resource</usage_type>
      <checksum>435C6B82</checksum>
    </file>
    <file>
      <filename>ControllerOutdoorAirFlow.rb</filename>
      <filetype>rb</filetype>
      <usage_type>resource</usage_type>
      <checksum>2946E820</checksum>
    </file>
  </files>
</measure>
